Dear fellow practitioners, during the
Kính thưa các quý đạo hữu lúc đi diễu
three processions on the evening of the 7th, the afternoon of the 8th,
hành ba buổi là tối mùng 7 trưa mùng 8
and the evening of the 8th, many people showed signs of
và tối mùng 8 có nhiều người tỏ vẻ mỏi
fatigue, but many others were not
mệt nhưng cũng có rất nhiều người không
tired and remained joyful until the very end. I
mỏi mệt vẫn hân hoan cho đến phút cuối
don't know if it's simply due to health,
con không biết đơn giản là do sức khỏe
age, or some other reason why the two groups of
hay tuổi tác hay nhân gì mà hai nhóm
people had such different feelings.
người có cảm Thọ khác nhau như vậy Kính
Dear fellow practitioners, it is called a
thưa quý đạo hữu người ta gọi là tâm
joyful mind, and with it, one can
hoan hỷ thì người ta sẽ
accomplish everything in the present moment.
làm được tất cả mọi việc trong hiện tại
Therefore, many people who
các quý đạo hữu ạ Cho nên có nhiều người
feel unwell can
sức khỏe cảm giác không đi được người ta
still go; this is because of the joyful mind they have.
vẫn đi được đó là do tâm hoan hỷ của mọi
We anticipate and contemplate
người chúng ta đón chờ chúng ta tư duy
that day, and sometimes, at
cái ngày đó thế nào và đôi khi người ta
first, they feel tired. But they persevere, and
có lúc đầu người ta thấy mệt Người ta cố
that effort
gắng thịt do cái tâm cố gắng đấy nó phát
generates the strength of diligence, and they
sinh cái lực tinh tấn và người ta sẽ trở
become tireless. On the other hand, there are
nên không mệt mỏi các đạo hữu ạ Thế còn
those who, at the slightest fatigue, immediately think about
có những người thì hơi mệt một tí là
resting and
chúng ta đã nghĩ đến chuyện nghỉ rồi
no longer think about the Dharma, so
chúng ta không nghĩ đến pháp nữa cho nên
they are carried away by the fatigue.
chúng ta sẽ bị cái mệt Nó kéo đi thôi
Do you understand, dear practitioners? Therefore,
Các Quý đạo hiện rõ chưa ạ Thế cho nên
there are those in the group of people...  Without fatigue and with
có những người ở nhóm người mà không mệt
joy, those who have a diligent mind
hoan hỷ là những người người ta có tâm
will, through this, the mind of Hoan Quan will
thì qua việc này tâm chiếu Hoàn quán sẽ
tell the story of a fellow practitioner who recently passed away. The
kể chuyện của đạo hữu the mới mất đấy ạ
fellow practitioner was the head of the
đạo hữu theo là đạo tràng trưởng của đạo
Thai Pho Quang Trung Thanh Hoa Dharma Center.
tràng Thái Phổ Quang Trung Thanh Hóa hôm
Today, the mind of Hoan Quan will tell you all
nay tâm chiếu Hoàn quán kể cho các quý
that when the fellow practitioner passed away, in the
thì khi đạo hữu theo mất ấy thì ở trong
mind of Hoan Quan,
tâm ở trong cảm thọ của tâm chiếu Hoàn
there was
quán nó có
a premonition. That is, before that,
cái cảm ứng tức là trước lúc đấy rồi thì
the mind of Hoan Quan knew that it had a
tâm chiếu của con mới biết là mình có
premonition before the Buddhist practitioner passed away. So, even though
cảm ứng từ trước lúc phật tử theo mất
the mind of Hoan Quan was very
cho nên đến lúc mà tâm chiếu ở quán rất
busy, somehow it opened
là bận thế nhưng mà lại làm sao lại mở
the page and immediately saw the deputy Dharma center's contact information.
cái trang ra thấy luôn của đạo tràng phó
The mind of Hoan Quan called
thế là tâm chiếu Hoàn quán gọi điện lại
the deputy Dharma center and immediately guided him in
cho đạo tràng phó và hướng dẫn luôn cho
preparing for the Buddhist practitioner's death, from the time the Buddhist practitioner was
chuẩn bị các việc từ lúc phật tử theo
still alive to the time of the emergency.
chưa mất mới là đi cấp cứu
And after the Buddhist practitioner passed away, the mind
thế và sau khi phật tử theo mất thì tâm
of Hoan Quan was busy. Because the
chiếu Hoàn quán đang bận mà Bởi vì Phật
Buddhist practitioner passed away on April 14th,
tử theo mất ngày 14 tháng 4 là lúc bấy
the mind of Hoan Quan was still
giờ là tâm chiếu Hoàn quán vẫn còn đang
busy. On the 15th, there were many ceremonies, and
bận ngày 15 thì bao nhiêu lễ
from the 14th to the 15th, the mind of
thì từ ngày 14 đến ngày 15 là tâm chiếu
Hoan Quan was busy.  A
Hoàn quán có một cái cái cảm ứng
very strong emotional response, a profound
cảm ứng rất là nhiều
contemplation, caused me to cry, and naturally,
tâm chiếu Hoàn quán có khóc và tự nhiên
within my heart, there was a feeling of deep compassion and a strong
ở trong tâm mình nó có một cái cảm Thọ
urge.
thôi thúc
Therefore, the contemplation led me to make
vì thế cho nên tâm chiếu Hoàn quán mới
the decision to inform
có cái quyết định thông báo lên là tất
all future Dharma group leaders that this is the
cả các đạo tràng trưởng sau này có quy
rule, as you, dear Dharma friends, have already
định là như thế các quý Đạo Hữu đã được
read. It was an extremely unusual feeling, dear
đọc rồi đấy nó có một cái cảm ứng vô
Dharma friends. And after the contemplation
các quý đạo hữu ạ và sau khi tâm chiếu
decided to go with the Dharma friends, the
Hoàn quán quyết định đi về với đạo hữu
contemplation ceased to have
theo thì tâm chiếu một quán mới hết cái
that feeling. It was truly a feeling that
cảm ứng đó nó có một cái cảm ứng Đúng là
the Buddha taught: the spiritual connection and the spread of thoughts and feelings are
Đức Phật dạy rằng cảm ứng đạo giao lan
inconceivable. That is the
tư nghỉ không thể nghĩ bàn đó là cái sức
power of the Dharma friends' diligence;
tinh tấn của đạo hữu theo
from that diligence,
từ cái sức tinh tấn đó
there was a response to the contemplation of the
nó có cảm ứng đến tâm chiếu Hoàn quán
Dharma friends. The Dharma friends, who had
đạo hữu theo
suffered from
là nhóm trưởng mà Đạo Hữu đã bị bệnh
lupus for 17 years, with all their internal
Lupus ban đỏ 17 năm hoàn toàn các nội
organs failing, still tried their best
tạng đã suy hết rồi nhưng vẫn cố gắng
to be Dharma group leaders because no one else in that group could
làm đạo tràng trưởng vì ở nhóm đó không
do
ai làm được
it. The Dharma friends also attended the Buddha's Birthday celebrations on the
thế và đạo hữu theo đi dự Phật Đản mùng
7th and 8th, participating in the
7 mùng 8 đều đi diễu hành hết trong cố
parade, and on the 9th, they went to the emergency room.  My fellow practitioners,
gắng về mùng 9 đi cấp cứu
at the 14th, you
các quý đạo hữu ạ và đến 14 thì đạo hữu
relinquished your physical body.
xả bỏ báo thân
This is a great blessing, and today, as I
Đây là một cái Phước báo và hôm nay tâm
contemplate and offer incense, I
chiếu Hoàn quán về thắp hương lên thì
know that you have been living in a
biết đạo hữu theo đã được ở trong cái
very happy and joyful state. You
cảnh sống rất là hạnh phúc rất là sung
told me, "On the
thế mà đạo hữu theo con nói với Tâm
day you
chiếu Hoàn quán là Cái hôm mà đạo hữu
went to the Buddha's birthday celebration, you
then đi đi giữa Phật Đản đấy
saw everyone was very
thì đạo hữu theo thấy mọi người rất là
joyful and healthy, and you
hoan hỷ và khỏe mạnh thì đạo hữu theo
rejoiced in your efforts. That's why you had this
hoan hỷ trong sự cố gắng cho nên đạo
thought: that you
cũng theo mới Khởi ý thế này khởi ý là
wished your body would be free from illness so
mong làm sao thân mình không có bệnh
you could attend the
mình được đi dự lễ
joyful ceremony. And that very wish led to the
hoan hỷ và chính cái mong đó đã khiến
elimination of evil karma and the relinquishing of your physical
tiêu trừ các cái ác nghiệp xả bỏ được
body. You have been
báo thân các quý đạo hữu ạ
diligent to such an extent that
tinh tấn đến mức độ như thế cho nên cái
this diligence has a spiritual connection. I
sự tinh tấn đó có sự cảm ứng và tâm
affirm that,
chiếu Hoàn quán khẳng định rằng đương
naturally, from the moment you were about to
nhiên là khi mà đạo hữu theo từ lúc mà
relinquish your physical body until the moment you did, there
sắp xả báo thân cho đến xả báo thân thì
will be Buddhas, Bodhisattvas,
đương nhiên là sẽ có chư phật bồ tát
holy monks, and Dharma protectors descending upon you. That
thánh tăng hộ pháp ứng giáng ở tại nơi
is inevitable, my fellow
đạo hữu theo điều đó là không thể không
practitioners. That's how
có các quý đạo hữu ạ
diligence works; it has a result."  It's
Đấy sự tinh tấn là như vậy nó có kết quả
truly valuable today. The mind-reading and the
rất là giá trị hôm nay tâm chiếu Hoàn
complete contemplation explained to the family: "
quán cũng nói cho gia đình nghe Cái bệnh
What kind of disease is this? It's the complete failure of all internal
này là cái bệnh gì là suy toàn bộ nội
organs, living in the hospital and relying on
tạng sống trong bệnh viện và sự phục vụ
family care. In the final stage, the
của người nhà và đến thời kỳ cuối cùng
flesh rots because the
thối thịt vì nó không còn cái cái hệ
immune system is completely destroyed. Before
miễn dịch của nó hỏng rồi và trước khi
dying, there must be a period of intense heat and
chết phải có thời gian nằm nhiệt và thối
flesh decay, a very painful process. The
thịt rất là khổ rồi mới chết được cái
disease is painful and causes redness,
bệnh nó buốt ban đỏ vốn dĩ là như thế
but you, fellow practitioners, didn't suffer like
thế nhưng mà đạo hữu theo không bị như
that. Don't you feel happy? Very
vậy có thấy hạnh phúc không Rất hạnh
happy to have eliminated all those karmic debts
phúc tiêu hết được các cái tội nghiệp
and to be focused on the Bodhi Mind.
đấy và chú được trong cái Niệm Bồ Đề cho
So when the mind-reading and the complete contemplation came, you were
nên khi tâm chiếu Hoàn quán về đạo hữu
very joyful and happy in
rất là Hoan Hỷ vui vẻ trong cảnh sống
your blissful state. Then, the mind-
thần tiên của mình Thế thì tâm chiếu
reading and the complete contemplation reminded you, and you continued to
Hoàn quán nhắc thôi vẫn tiếp tục thực
practice the Bodhi virtues. You were very
hành công hạnh Bồ Đề Đạo Hữu rất hoan hỷ
happy, dear fellow practitioners. And today, your family was very happy. After
của đạo hữu rất là Hoan Hỷ thế và sau
the ceremony, your younger sister
cái buổi lễ thì em của đạo hữu em gái
volunteered to work
của đạo hữu cũng xung phong vào làm
in the Dharma center to help out.
trong đạo tràng để trợ giúp cho đạo
That's the blessing you
tràng đấy là cái Phước của đạo hữu theo
left for your family, is
để lại cho gia đình mình đấy các đạo hữu
n't
phải không
it?"  That diligence, that merit, is meant to
cái sự tinh tấn đấy Cái phước đấy để lại
benefit one's own family. My younger brother
độ cho ngay người nhà mình thôi Em trai
also agrees to join the Dharma center with joy.
cũng đồng ý sẽ vào đạo tràng hoan hỷ đấy
That merit benefits one's family; who one benefits depends on oneself,
phước đấy độ được cho người nhà mình độ
right? If you want to help someone,
lực phải không Mình có muốn độ cho ai
but you don't make an effort, you ca
nhưng bản thân mình không nỗ lực thì
n't. The
không thể độ được đấy đạo hữu theo mới
Dharma center was just established on
thành lập Đạo tràng có hôm
December 8th, in December. It was
tháng 12 đấy mùng 8 tháng 12 đấy các đạo
just transferred from the founding guidance committee
mới từ ban hướng dẫn thành lập Đạo tràng
to the establishment of the Dharma center on
chuyển sang thành lập Đạo tràng hôm mùng
December 8th. Today, everyone is
8 tháng 12 mà hôm nay về mọi người ôn
reminiscing about the memories of the Dharma center's illness.
lại cái kỷ niệm của đạo hữu theo bệnh
So many people in the Dharma
như thế mà bao nhiêu người trong đạo
center have undergone karmic transformation. All the esteemed Dharma members have benefited
tràng Chuyển Nghiệp các quý đạo hữu đều
from the guidance of the Dharma center's mind and the complete contemplation. It's incredibly moving.
do đạo hữu theo hướng dẫn cả tâm chiếu
How could the Buddhas not
như vậy thì làm sao mà chư phật không
descend to protect and support them? Even with such a body afflicted by illness, he has
ứng giáng hộ Trì thân mang bệnh như thế
helped so many people and families
mà giúp bao nhiêu người rất nhiều nhà
transform their karma in that Dharma center. He has
chuyển nghiệp trong cái đạo tràng ấy
done so much, and everyone
Chuyển việc nhiều lắm các đạo hữu mà ai
mentions the Dharma center's encouragement. Even with a body afflicted by
cũng nhắc đến Đạo Hữu the đạo hữu theo
illness, he persevered
sách tấn cho đấy thân bệnh mà chịu khó
so hard, even his internal organs were weakened.
như thế các quý Đạo Hữu suy hết nội tạng
That's how it is
Đấy
here.  So, we have too much attachment to our family,
Thế ở đây thì chúng ta có ái thân chúng
don't we? A little tired, a
ta quá không phải không hơi mệt một tí
little difficult, and we get discouraged.
thì không tu hơi khó khăn một tí thì nản
Seeing fellow practitioners following and
chí đấy Nhìn thấy đạo hữu theo mà phấn
striving, that's why there's such a connection, a
đấu cho nên Tại sao nó có cái cảm ứng
mind-reading, a complete contemplation. The connection is
đến tâm chiếu Hoàn quán như vậy cảm ứng
very strong. A mind-reading, a single contemplation, thinking
rất là nhiều tâm chiếu một quán nghĩ
that during illness, the intention followed, thinking of the
rằng trong lúc bệnh đạo ý theo nghĩ đến
Three Jewels, thinking of oneself, taking refuge,
tam bảo đến nghĩ đến mình rất nhiều
so there was a miraculous thing. That very
cho nên có cái sự vi diệu
day, the mind-reading, a
chính hôm đấy tâm chiếu một quán nó bạch
single contemplation, I reported to the master. I
chuyện của đạo hữu then là tâm chiếu một
reported to the master several times about the fellow practitioner following, I reported to the master
quán Bạch sư phụ mấy lần liền đều kể
that there was such a fellow practitioner, a Dharma center leader. And I
phụ là có đạo Hữu Đạo tràng trưởng như
had this feeling, I was
vậy thế mà con thì có một cái cảm thức
very connected to the diligent fellow practitioners.
đứa con rất là cảm ứng với các đạo hữu
Then the master said that this
tinh tấn Thế thì sư phụ có nói rằng đây
is a connection due to the Bodhi Vow.
là cảm ứng do Hạnh Nguyện Bồ Đề Những
Those who truly practice the Bodhi Vow
người chân thật thực hành Nguyện Bồ đề
will have such a connection. And
thì sẽ có cảm ứng như vậy thế và chính
the act of visiting the fellow practitioners, the Dharma
cái việc mà thăm viếng các đạo Hữu Đạo
center leader, plus the Four Gratitudes to Parents, the
tràng trưởng cộng với Tứ Ân Phụ Mẫu của
Dharma center leader—this is the
đạo Trọng trưởng đây là trong đấy là ý
master's intention. Of course, the mind-reading, a complete contemplation,
của sư phụ Tất nhiên là tâm chiếu Hoàn
that's the master's intention.  That
quán ý đó nhưng tâm sư phụ bảo kinh đó
's the correct explanation because the Dharma center leaders
là cái đúng bởi vì những người đạo tràng
belong to the Bodhi Mind,
trưởng người ta là thuộc về Tâm Bồ Đề hi
sacrificing for all their followers, guiding the followers
sinh cho tất cả phật tử của mình dẫn dắt
in the Dharma center. A Dharma
cho Phật tử trong đạo tràng cho người
center leader who truly practices the
đạo tràng trưởng mà chân thật thực hành
Dharma, obeys and
theo pháp của quả chân thật vâng lời và
practices, will always have the protection
thực hành là bao giờ cũng có sự bảo hộ
of the Buddhas, Bodhisattvas, and holy Sangha protectors. The true master
của chư Phật Bồ Tát thánh tăng Hộ Pháp
also said
đấy Những người chân thật sư phụ còn nói
that one must pay homage to the diligent practice of cultivation.
là phải đảnh lễ cái
Therefore, the Mind-Viewing and Complete Contemplation tells you, dear Dharma center leaders, that if you see the Dharma center
đấy các quý đạo hữu cho nên tâm chiếu
breaking up a little, there will be an
tràng đâm lên một chút thấy tách ra nó
opportunity for others to become Dharma center leaders. That's exactly it.
có cơ hội cho người khác làm đạo tràng
Those of you who are
trưởng chính là như thế đấy những đạo
diligent in the leadership committee,
hữu là tinh tấn trong ban cán sự
try to become Dharma center leaders. That is
hãy cố gắng làm đạo tràng trưởng đấy là
a very auspicious opportunity, dear Dharma center leaders.
một cái duyên rất Thù Thắng các quý đạo
Therefore, today, the Mind-Viewing and Complete Contemplation is very joyful to
Cho nên là hôm nay tâm chiếu Hoàn quán
visit the
Rất là Hoan Hỷ khi về thăm viếng gia
families of Dharma center members and meet
đình đạo hữu theo gặp gỡ
them in this new life. The Mind-
đạo hữu của mình trong kiếp sống mới tâm
Viewing and Complete Contemplation is very joyful. If the
chiếu Hoàn quán rất hoan hỷ nếu như tâm
Mind-Viewing and Complete Contemplation still has a lifespan in this
tâm chiếu Hoàn quán còn cái Thọ mạng ở
world, then any Dharma center leader who abandons
trên đời thì đạo tràng trưởng nào mà bỏ
their physical body will also come to you,
báo thân tâm chiếu của con cũng đến các
dear Dharma center leaders.  If there is still life left, even if one
quý đạo hữu ạ Nếu còn Thọ mạng thì kể cả
becomes a monk or nun, one will still attain perfect
đi xuất gia rồi cũng đến
enlightenment. I deeply respect the
tâm chiếu Hoàn quán Rất là kính quý
true Dharma leaders.
những người đạo tràng trưởng thật sự
Today, encountering something like
là hôm nay gặp được một chuyện như thế
this, I feel very
này tâm chiếu Hoàn quán thấy rất là hạnh
happy because I was able to talk with
phúc bởi vì mình nói chuyện được với đạo
my fellow practitioners. I know my fellow practitioners are
hữu của mình Mình biết Đạo Hữu của mình
still continuing on the path of Bodhi, not
vẫn đi tiếp trên con đường Bồ Đề không
giving up. This is proof,
có bỏ vào đây là một minh chứng minh
proof that I am affirming that
chứng để tâm chiếu Hoàn quán khẳng định
on my path, I am guiding
trên con đường đi của mình là cho các
my fellow practitioners to develop Bodhi-mind. They will
đạo hữu của mình Phát Tâm Bồ Đề họ sẽ tự
walk the path of Bodhi on their own in the next life. At
đi trên con đường bồ đề trong kiếp sau
that time, I will have
tự họ đấy chứ lúc đấy tâm chiếu Hoàn
returned to enlighten them, and even if they don't follow, they will
quán đã về Khai Thị cho đạo ít theo đâu
still be walking on the path of Bodhi
đậu xe vẫn đã đi trên con đường bồ đề
in a very fulfilling life. It's
trong một kiếp sống rất đầy đủ các quý
very beautiful,
đạo hữu ạ rất đẹp
very complete, very joyful. That's why I
rất đầy đủ rất hoan hỷ cho nên tâm chiếu
told the family that if the fellow
Hoàn quán mới nói với gia đình là đạo
practitioner follows, the family doesn't need to
hữu theo thì không cần gia đình phải
make offerings or chant scriptures. But
cúng dường hết tụng kinh gì cả nhưng mà
this is something the family needs to do to bring blessings
đây là việc mà gia đình cần làm có phúc
to the family. We must live with
cho gia đình thôi chúng ta phải sống có
blessings and righteousness. If anyone makes offerings to the fellow practitioner,
phúc có nghĩa mà nếu ai mà cúng Đạo Hữu
the family will receive blessings and protection.
thì gia đình sẽ được phúc sẽ được gia hộ
Let's listen to this story.  Those
đấy chúng ta nghe với cái chuyện mà
who are born as female demons, we are
người sinh làm nữ dạ xoa đấy chúng ta là
diligent practitioners, and when we die,
người tinh tấn chúng ta chết đi thì
our loved ones only benefit from our presence. The
người thân chúng ta chỉ được nhờ thôi
righteous
sống còn được nhờ Chính Nghĩa là chết
path is to die today, with a mindful heart, gathering all the photos
hôm nay là tâm chốn quán là gom luôn ảnh
of our fellow practitioners and placing them on the ancestral altar.
của của đạo hữu lên trên ban thờ gia
Remove all the incense burners and the
tiên luôn Đưa hết bát hương lên Bỏ hết
altar for the deceased; we do
bát hương thờ cái cái ban thờ vong ấy đi
n't worship any spirits. We worship only to show
không có thờ vong gì cả thờ để gọi là
kinship and receive blessings,
tình thân để cho được gia hộ thôi chứ
not to worship any spirits at all, dear fellow
không có thờ vong thờ vong gì cả các quý
practitioners. It's so beautiful.
đạo hữu ạ Nó tốt đẹp như thế cơ mà chúng
We are practitioners who uphold the precepts, so when we
ta là người tu hành trì giới như thế
die, we don't become wandering hungry ghosts.
chết đâu có phải thành vong linh ngã quỷ
Our blessings are abundant, do you
phước báu của chúng ta đầy đủ
see? They practice the
thấy đúng không chúng nó thực hành công
Bodhisattva path. But remember to give up the
hạnh bồ đề Nhưng nhớ là phải chừa cái
habit of stealing. Once you steal food, once you
thói ăn cướp đi đã cướp đồ ăn đi đã
die, you are free and happy. You don't need
chết là chúng ta tự tại hạnh phúc cha
anyone to worry about you or scold you; you only need to worry
cần phải ai lo cho mình mà chửi mình lo
about everyone, dear fellow practitioners. You are very
cho mọi người thôi các quý đạo hữu rất
happy. So today, the whole family of our fellow
là hạnh phúc cho nên hôm nay cả nhà của
practitioners, in the atmosphere of the Dharma
đạo hữu the là trong không khí các đạo
centers, today, 11 Dharma centers in Thanh
tràng đến hôm nay 11 đạo tràng ở Thanh
Hoa, the Dharma center group, to our dear fellow practitioners.
Hóa nhóm đạo tràng đến các quý đạo hữu ạ
Just the Dharma center leader or the Fourfold End.
Cứ đạo tràng trưởng hoặc Tứ tận Ân Phụ
Wherever there is a problem with the parents of the spiritual group, people
Mẫu của đạo tràng tư tưởng ở đâu mà có
from a distance of 50 km or
vấn đề gì thì khu vực đó cứ từ 50 km trở
more gather to visit and pay their respects. It's
lên là hội tụ về hết để mà đi viếng thay
very joyful for today's club,
cho câu lạc bộ hôm nay rất là vui các
dear fellow practitioners. It's very joyful! The group
quý đạo hữu ạ rất là vui mà đạo tràng
leader here refers to someone who has already been a group leader,
trưởng ở đây là đã làm đạo tràng trưởng
not someone currently in the position.
thôi nhé chứ không tính là đang làm đạo
Because sometimes, after we become group
tràng trưởng vì có khi chúng ta làm đạo
leaders,
tràng Trưởng xong rồi chúng ta Nhỡ may
due to past karma, we might get sick or
do nghiệp quá khứ chúng ta ốm bệnh hoặc
we might hand over the leadership to younger generations for them to
chúng ta nhường lại cho lớp trẻ để nó
progress, right? We don't do it ourselves,
tiến bộ phải không Chúng ta không làm
but those who have been group leaders
nhưng mà người đã làm đạo tràng trưởng
also fall under this standard, dear fellow practitioners.
cũng trong tiêu chuẩn này các quý đạo
It's like the "Mind-Viewing Complete Contemplation" – if
hữu ạ Giống như tâm chiếu Hoàn quán đấy
we were group leaders and now
là mình làm đạo tràng trưởng rồi bây giờ
need someone else to be one, then
phải cần cho người khác làm đạo tràng
we have to step down to let
trưởng cho nên mình phải lui về để cho
someone else take over. That's what it means to have been a group
người khác làm thì là đã làm đạo tràng
leader, dear fellow practitioners. Whether you've been a
trưởng các quý đạo hữu rõ chưa đã làm
group leader or are currently one, it's all
đạo tràng trưởng hoặc đang làm đạo tràng
within that standard. Because
Trưởng cùng trong tiêu chuẩn đó Bởi vì
they deserve it, dear fellow practitioners. They
người ta đáng được như thế có quý đạo
deserve to be visited and
hữu ạ đáng được thăm viếng
praised.
đáng được tán dương những người đạo
Group leaders are people who deserve to be
tràng trưởng là những người đáng được
visited and praised;
tăng viếng đáng được tán dương cha mẹ
their parents gave birth to them.  We are the
người ta sinh cho người ta là những
ones who gave birth to these precious children, are
người sinh ra những người con Quý các
n't we, dear fellow practitioners? Therefore,
quý đạo hữu ạ phải không cho nên cha mẹ
their parents deserve our
những người đấy cũng đáng để cho chúng
attention, right? So, let's
ta thăm hỏi đúng không nhé Cho nên là cố
strive to be Dharma center leaders, dear fellow practitioners.
gắng mà làm đạo tràng trưởng các quý đạo
Speaking of Dharma center leaders, we have a very
hữu ạ đàm đạo tràng trưởng chúng ta có
auspicious connection.
nhân duyên Thù Thắng nhé
Today, 11 Dharma centers are going to the home of a fellow practitioner, and the
hôm nay 11 Đạo Tràng về nhà đạo hữu theo
whole family is joyful. Everyone is happy, dear fellow
cả nhà vui mừng tất cả vui mừng các quý
practitioners and Buddhists are also happy
đạo hữu các phật tử cũng vui mừng hoan
and joyful. In front of the house, there are cars and small cars parked, staring at the dear fellow practitioners. Going back and forth, there will be a long line of cars and large cars parked like this, it's very joyful. The parents are also very happy, and the
rất là vui cha mẹ cũng rất là vui người
family is also very happy, dear fellow practitioners.
nhà cũng rất là vui các quý đạo hữu nhé
So, especially later, when the
Cho nên là chúng ta nhất là sau này đám
parents of the Dharma center leader are at a funeral,
ma mà cha mẹ của đạo tràng trưởng thì
all the Dharma centers will come, and we will all be very
bao nhiêu đạo tràng đấy ta đến rất là
happy, right? That's why having
Hoan Hỷ phải không Đấy thì mình là có
friends like that is impossible.
những người bạn như thế thì không thể có
And whoever is diligent will eventually
thế và ai ai tinh tấn thì rồi ban cán sự
become a Dharma center leader, dear fellow practitioners. Whoever is diligent...
cũng thành hết đạo tràng trưởng thôi mà
Then they
các quý đạo hữu Ai tinh tấn rồi thành
all became Dharma centers because it happened so quickly. They
đạo tràng trưởng hết tại vì nó nhanh
quickly split into Dharma centers. It was just yesterday.
nhanh lắm Nhanh tách thành đạo tràng Mới
[music]
[âm nhạc]